# Viktor Mediankin

# Python Backend Developer

Phuket, Thailand +66-803-910-112 | medyankin.viktor@gmail.com | Linkedin | Telegram

## Summary

Professional Python Backend developer with 4+ years of experience designing and implementing Software and Machine Learning projects. I am proficient in Python, relevant Web Frameworks and Backend systems. I am seeking a challenging position that will allow me to contribute to an organization's success and drive exceptional results.

#### SKILLS

Programming: Python, Golang

Backend: REST, gRPC, Django, FastApi, Flask, SQL, PostgreSQL, Cassandra, Redis, Kafka, Celery

ML/BigData: Airflow, MLflow, Seldon-Core, Spark, numpy, pandas, pytorch

DevOps: Gitlab-CI, Docker, Docker-Compose, Kubernetese

## EXPERIENCE

## Python Backend Developer

Aug. 2021 – Present

Remote

 $Alfa\text{-}Bank,\ MLOps\ team$ 

- Implemented a Python-based Machine Learning platform with end-to-end supervised model deployment capabilities, resulting in a reduction of new model deployment time from one week to just a few hours. The platform currently handles a high volume of one hundred thousand user requests daily.
- Built a real-time chatbot using Python and deployed it on Telegram Messenger for assessing employees, resulting in 18,000 employees engaging with the assessment. This amounted to 70% of the total number of employees.
- Developed and optimized data processing pipeline with Apache Airflow, achieving a significant 60% increase in data processing efficiency. The optimized pipeline directly contributed to the accelerated development speed of machine learning products used by millions of users.

## **Backend Developer**

Golang Backend Developer

Sep. 2019 – Aug. 2021

Remote

AtsAero, voice assistants product team

Mar. 2021 - Aug. 2021

• Created streaming service using Golang to manage audio content in Smart IVR system. Achieved a 30% improvement in call routing and processing time, resulting in a more responsive and efficient system used by 10s of thousands of users.

#### Python Backend Developer

Sep. 2019 - Mar. 2021

- Developed a REST API service that improved intent recognition accuracy, making the virtual assistant smarter, leading to a 60% drop in call drops and a 40% rise in successful call completions for thousands of daily callers.
- Built Python-based NLP SDK that increased automated requests by 30% and raised customer satisfaction by 25% in post-call surveys, allowing for improved customer experience and efficiency. New feature attracted \$200k investments.

## Python Backend Developer

Oct. 2018 - Sep. 2019

Gazpromneft Oil and Gas Science and Technology Center

Remote

• Developed a Django-based hydrodynamic modeling module for providing customers with accurate simulations. Reduced reliance on external commercial software by 40%, saving \$300k annually in licensing costs.

# EDUCATION

# Gubkin Russian State University of Oil and Gas

Russia, Moscow

Mechanics and mathematical modeling for Oil and Gas transportation, Master

Sep. 2012 - May 2018

## AWARDS

## Selectel Hackathon 2019, selectel.ru

Russia, St.Petersburg

3rd. 4challenge. Library management system

Oct. 2019